“基辅－乌克兰共和国首都”
幸好…
你找了我们
我不知道发生了什么事
我们俩在酒吧…
喝酒…
玩得很开心…
我连怎么到的这里… 都不知道
快啊, 她假死得太久了
Come on, come on. She's been under too long.
只有你能帮我了
快点
把我想知道的告诉我
快说
他们会杀了我的
是你找我们帮你的
快说吧
快
Come on.
在明斯克的联络人是…
告诉我们名字, 伙计
The name, pal. Give us the name.
季米治… 密地夫
现在要做什么?
我们来喝杯酒
Za druziye
把那个人渣弄走
Get rid of that scum.
嘉丽, 醒醒…
Claire, come on...
问出来了吗?
Did we get it?
问出来了
We got it.
【 职 业 特 工 队 】
你要看部电影吗, 费先生?
Would you like to watch a movie, Mr. Rosen?
不了, 谢谢
No, thank you.
你要看部电影吗, 费尔普斯先生?
Would you like to watch a movie, Mr. Phelps?
不了, 我更喜欢看戏剧
No. I prefer the theater.
看看这部乌克兰的影片怎么样?
Would you consider the cinema of the Ukraine?
要不你帮我挑一部吧
Perhaps you'll choose one for me.
谢谢
Thank you.
早上好, 费尔普斯先生
Good morning, Mr. Phelps.
你现在看见的这个男人是亚历山大·葛里森
The man you're looking at is Alexander Golitsyn...
我国驻布拉格大使馆馆员
an attache at our embassy in Prague.
也是一个叛徒
He is also a traitor.
他偷取了中央情报局 NOC 名单的一半 (NOC: 非官方掩护, CIA 最敏感和最秘密的计划)
He has stolen one half of a C.I.A. NOC list--
这是一份记录了所有 在东欧工作的极机密特工的资料
a record of all our deep-cover agents working in Eastern Europe.
出于安全原因, NOC 名单是分成两份的
For security reasons, the NOC list is divided in two.
葛里森手里的那部分记录了特工代号
The portion that Golitsyn already has contains code names...
但是如果没有另一半 它是没有任何价值的
but this half is useless without its mate...
另一半记录了和特工代号匹配的真实姓名
which matches the code names with their true names.
葛里森计划在明晚酒会上 从大使馆偷出另一半名单
It is this half which Golitsyn plans to steal from the embassy during a reception tomorrow night.
占士, 你可以选择是否接下这个任务:
Your mission, Jim, should you choose to accept it...
拿到葛里森偷窃和交易过程的录像证据, 并将他们全部逮捕
is to obtain photographic proof of the theft shadow Golitsyn to his buyer and apprehend them both.
我们已经派出了由你手下组成的行动组
We've already dispatched a team selected from your usual group--
莎拉·戴维斯已经在大使馆卧底
Sarah Davies is already under cover...
杰克·哈门可以破解所有的安全系统
Jack Harmon can hack into any security system...
汉娜·威廉斯善于监视
Hannah Williams will handle surveillance...
你的太太嘉丽负责掩护和交通
your wife, Claire, will cover transport...
还有依顿·韩特和往常一样做你的先锋
and Ethan Hunt will be your point man as usual.
他现在正在基辅, 会在布拉格的指定地点会合
He is now in Kiev and will rendezvous in Prague...
就是你选的那个安全屋里
at a safe house of your choosing.
像往常一样, 如果你或者 行动小组的任何成员被逮捕或者被杀
As always, should you or any member of your l.M. force be caught or killed...
部长会否认对你们这次行动的知情
the secretary will disavow all knowledge of your actions.
这盘带子会在五秒钟之后自动销毁
This tape will self-destruct in five seconds.
祝你好运, 占士
Good luck, Jim.
布拉格
任务目标很简单
A very straightforward objective--
拍下葛里森偷取 NOC 名单的过程
We photograph Golitsyn stealing the NOC list...
然后跟踪他到交易地点
follow him to his buyer...
最后把他们全部逮捕
apprehend both of them.
现在说一下行动计划
Now here's the plot.
依顿, 你改扮之后进入大使馆参加酒会
Ethan, you're going into the embassy in character during a party.
尽量引起注意
Hide in plain sight-- highest possible profile.
这样可以吗?
Are you game?
不会再有更好的方式了
Wouldn't have it any other way.
莎拉, 你也要参加酒会
Sarah, you're at the party already...
做为大使馆的华盛顿来宾的联络员
as the embassy's Washington visitor liaison.
和依顿接触
Make contact with Ethan.
你和他一起行动
You'll run the game together.
我没有酒会上的穿戴
I haven't a thing to wear.
喔, 我相信你会弄到的
Well, I'm sure you'll work it out.
你要在葛里森身上做个记号, 然后告诉汉娜他的位置
You'll Mark Golitsyn, hand him off to Hannah.
汉娜, 你要在酒会期间一直监视他
Hannah, you'll have him for the duration of the interior.
找一个有利的位置然后盯住他
Find yourself a perch and stay on him.
没问题
No problem.
-杰克 -什么?
-Jack... -Yeah?
指纹认证系统-- 进入电梯前要通过这个
fingerprint security-- There's access through the elevator shaft here.
所以我估计我是没机会穿礼服了
So I guess I'm not wearing my tux.
开启, 关闭, 然后离开
Open, close, get out.
不要留下任何痕迹
Zero residual presence.
嘉丽, 你在外面的车内掩护
Claire, you're cover outside in the vehicle.
葛里森出来之后汉娜会和你一起, 你们两个在那里监视他
Hannah will join you as Golitsyn goes exterior you two stay on him from there.
一旦出现了差错我会呼叫中止任务
Anything goes wrong, I call abort--
所有人立即离开
everybody walk away immediately.
凌晨四点的时候在这里会合
Regroup here at 4 a.m. That's 0400.
还有什么问题吗?
Any questions?
有
Yeah.
能不能弄个咖啡壶?
Can we get a cappuccino machine in here?
因为我都不知道 该怎么称呼这个难喝的东西
'Cause I don't know what you call this.
我称它为痛苦残忍和不同寻常
I call it cruel and unusual.
那些咖啡是我沏的
I made that coffee.
没错, 它是不是比你 在基辅的马厩里弄的污水还难喝?
Exactly. Is it possible it's even worse than that sludge you made in that barn in Kiev?
别嫌弃我太太沏的咖啡, 好吗?
Hey, take it easy on my wife's coffee, will you?
我们在基辅很想念你, 占士
We missed you in Kiev, Jim.
我也很想你, 依顿
Missed you, too, Ethan.
又是刚刚结束舒适的招募新人的任务?
Off on one of your cushy recruiting assignments again?
这次他们让你住在哪儿了? 纽约大饭店?
Where'd they put you up this time? The Plaza?
芝加哥德雷克大饭店
Drake Hotel, Chicago.
太舒适了! 二十四小时客房服务
Cushy! 24-hour room service.
配备私人司机的轿车
Chauffeured cars.
又是一大笔报销单
Fat expense account.
他开始享受晚年的乐趣了
He's getting soft in his old age.
就是, 看看他
Yeah, he is. Look at him.
好了, 听着
O.K., listen.
如果这个名单流传出去并被公开了
If that list gets out into the open...
我们所有在东欧国家的特工的名字…
the names of our agents in every country in Eastern Europe...
就会被第三世界的恐怖分子、 军火商、毒枭这些人轻松地高价入手
will be up for grabs to the highest bidders-- third world terrorists, arms dealers, drug lords...
他们一直都想除掉像我们这种隐蔽的特工
any and everybody who'd love to get rid of long-term coverts like us.
一旦他们被暴露了, 就会被处决
If they're exposed, they'll be executed.
所以, 我会在这里进行指挥
So, I'll run the whole show from the crow's nest here.
所有人都清楚自己的角色任务
Everyone knows their roles.
记录一下详细资料吧
Let's punch out the details.
鼻梁右边设有相机
There's a camera built right into the bridge.
你看到的东西它都会采集到
Whatever you see, it sees...
然后它会传送到这里, 看见了吗?
and then it transmits it back here. See?
能听见我吗?
Can you hear me?
我当然能听见你
Of course I can hear you.
不是的, 在你的… 喔, 你需要一个听筒
No, in your-- Oh, you need an earpiece.
你的眼睛很迷人
You have lovely eyes.
现在能听见我了吗?
Can you hear me now?
非常响亮清晰
Loud and clear.
如果他开车跑了, 你无论如何都要跟住他
If he has a car waiting, and he rolls you stay with him no matter what.
你应该利用下午时间 多开车逛逛这个地区的街道
You should take the afternoon drive the streets around this little quarter.
他们会疯狂地绕路的
They're confusing as hell.
你以为我一个上午都做了什么
What do you think I've been doing all morning?
我们要用华尔兹?
We're using Waltzer?
他是我们的人啊
He's our guy.
他没在主持军方听证会?
Isn't he chairing the Armed Services hearing?
不是这周
Not this week.
这个星期他飞去 基尔代尔郡的奥特阿德沼泽钓鱼去了
This week, he's fly fishing at the Oughterard Slough in County Kildare...
带着我们一个最好的爱尔兰导游
with one of our best lrish guides.
是的, 而且他肯定不会马上回来的
Yup. And he won't be back anytime soon.
…顶多是跑题了
...irrelevant at best...
或者最差的情况是违反了宪法
or unconstitutional at worst.
恕我直言, 议员
With all due respect, Senator...
你想发起的指控听起来很像 弗兰克·丘奇议员在1970年的那次
it sounds as if you want to lead the kind of charge that Senator Frank Church led in the 1970s...
那次导致了这个国家情报机能的毁坏
and in the process destroy the intelligence capability of this country.
不是, 现在我只是想知道那些人是谁, 还有他们是如何挥霍纳税人的钱的
No. Now, I want to know who these people are and how they're spending our taxpayers' money.
我再次重申, 我们是生活在民主社会里的
We were living in a democracy the last time I checked.
一块口香糖, 对吧?
Stick of gum, right?
不是吗?
No?
不是的, 红灯, 绿灯
No. Red light, green light.
你碰到打不开的锁时, 你把它们揉在一起
You come up against a lock you can't pick you mash them together--
(俄语), 千万不要弄到自己身上
Hasta lasagna, don't get any on ya.
你大概有五秒钟的时间
You'll have about five seconds.
可别嚼了它
Just don't chew it.
依顿, 杰克已经就位了
Ethan, Jack's inside.
行动吧
Let's go.
你好吗, 议员? 我是兰特·奥斯曼, 大使的副官
How do you do, Senator? I'm Rand Housman, the ambassador's aide.
你好, 兰特·奥斯曼先生
Hello, Mr. Housman.
歌剧怎么样?
How was the opera?
很无聊的
Uh, it was boring.
让我带您先进去
Let me see if I can steer you through this reception line.
你好吗, 议员?
How do you do, Senator?
他的太太, 里德夫人
His wife, Mrs. Reed.
在2300端口上打开视窗
Windows open by 2300.
毕特·布兰, 布拉格市长
Petr Brandl, the mayor of Prague...
-你好 -还有布兰夫人
How do you do? and Mrs. Brandl.
我打赌你已经认不得我了, 是吧?
I bet you don't remember me, do you?
当然认得, 你好啊, 诺曼小姐
Of course I do. How are you, Miss Norman?
已经确认他在楼梯那里
He's in pocket, on the stairway.
葛里森先生, 真高兴见到你
Mr. Golitsyn, nice to see you.
汉娜
Hannah...
去掉颜色
pull the shade.
莎拉, 在目标上做标记, 然后去二楼
Sarah, mark the package and go to two.
您的高级小组 提起您喜欢在交通工具上观光
Your advance team mentioned you'd like a tour of the facility...
所以我们就去装配一个吧
so I've gone ahead and set one up.
请这边
Excuse me. This way.
噢, 太棒了
Oh, great.
这里通往大使馆里唯一的管制区
...which leads to the denied area the only limited-access area in the whole facility.
管理员现在要过去了
Governor's in position now.
对不起, 我可以帮忙吗?
Excuse me. Can I help you?
噢, 对不起
Oh, I'm sorry.
就像你看到的, 这里有保安, 还有监视器
As you can see, there's a marine guard and video surveillance...
这里就好像--不好意思
This place is like--Excuse me. I'm sorry.
我知道它就在包里的某个地方
I know it's in here somewhere.
上士, 你在晚会上为什么不穿制服?
Sergeant, why are you not in your uniform this evening?
我们奉命穿着便装
Uh, we've been ordered to wear civilian clothes...
只是这个晚上, 长官
this evening, sir.
马上就回来
Be right back.
议员, 请告诉我你的手下有叫杰克的吗?
Tell me, Senator, do you have someone on your staff named Jack?
杰克? 我们的确有个叫做杰克的人
Jack? Uh, we did have a Jack.
一个很不可靠的家伙, 记得他经常迟到
An unreliable fellow, as I recall--constantly late...
而且工作拖沓
and behind in his work.
我们强行把他系在好马后面 拖着他绕着我的谷仓走了好几天
We were forced to tie him behind one of my best stallions and drag him around my barn for a few days.
不要急啊, 我正在处理
Relax your crack, Foghorn. I'm working on it.
档案输入警卫站...
身份符合：准许进入
抱歉让你久等, 长官
Sorry, sir.
谢谢, 晚上愉快
Thank you. Have a nice evening.
谢谢
Thank you. Come.
你和莎拉的约会肯定是没戏了
That date with Sarah is definitely off.
再高点
Higher.
他往管制区那里去了
He's heading to the denied area.
快点, 依顿, 他往你那里去了
Get moving, Ethan. He's rolling to you.
杰克
Jack.
杰克, 我们已经就位了
Jack, we're in position here.
杰克
Jack.
不是我弄的
I didn't touch it.
我的外衣哪儿去了? 出去会很冷的
What about my coat? I'll freeze.
杰克, 快打开门
Jack, open the doors.
他在电梯里, 依顿, 他已经在电梯里了
He's in the box, Ethan. He's in the box.
知道了
O.K....
我们就快和葛里森碰上了
we're taking Golitsyn's exit.
快打开门
Open these doors.
我现在也没办法
I don't have it.
我来开门吧, 从底下走
I'm opening the doors. Go under.
快走
Go.
他已经拿到了
He's got it.
好的
All right.
我又救了你的屁股一命, 杰克
Saved your ass again, Jack.
让我休息一下, 老爹
Give me a break, pops.
那么美的一个屁股
Such a nice ass.
还是个寂寞的屁股
And a lonely ass.
五分钟后到车上去
Transport in five minutes.
好的
Yes, indeed.
杰克, 我们就位了
Jack, we're in position.
打开门让目标出去
Open the doors and let the package roll.
收到, 正在开门
Roger that. Opening doors now.
汉娜, 你的任务完成了
Stairway, you're wrapped.
到车上去
Go to transport.
杰克, 你在干什么?
Jack, what are you doing?
我什么都没做啊
I'm not doing anything.
系统处理有误
我无法控制了, 杰克
I don't have control, Jack.
那我麻烦大了
Uh, then I got a problem.
切断电源
Cut the power.
切断电源, 杰克
Cut the power, Jack.
快点, 杰克
Come on, Jack.
切断电源
Cut the power.
杰克…
Jack...
杰克?
Jack?
杰克, 收到了吗?
Jack, do you copy?
杰克?
Jack?
队员牺牲了, 依顿
Man down, Ethan.
他死了
Man down.
依顿, 待在现在的位置别动
Ethan, stay where you are.
我去找你
I'm coming to you.
目标已经离开大使馆
The package is out in the open.
占士
Jim...
他已经在使馆外面了
he's in the open.
我正在路上
En route.
占士, 他已经在使馆外面了
Jim, he's in the open.
占士, 目标已经在使馆外面了
Jim, the package is in the open.
我被跟踪了
I've got a shadow.
你能甩掉他吗?
Can you lose him?
不行, 中止任务
No. Abort.
依顿, 他要离开控制范围了
Ethan, he's out of pocket.
不能跟踪他吗?
Can't do that.
我们中埋伏了, 依顿
We're being ambushed, Ethan.
中止任务, 这是命令
Abort. That's an order.
我拒绝, 葛里森正在行动
Negative. Golitsyn is on the move.
不行, 混蛋! 不行! 我说了中止任务!
No, damn it! No! I said abort!
莎拉, 盯住目标, 占士, 我现在往你那里去了
Sarah, eye on the package. Jim, I'm coming to you.
占士已经说中止任务了, 我们应该马上离开
Jim gave an abort. We should walk away.
不行, 我们必须取回那张磁盘
No. We are going to recover that disk.
你明白吗?
You understand me?
现在就去
Now go!
你在哪?
Where are you?
离桥大概二百码
About 200 yards from the bridge.
他们监听了我们的波段
They're covering this frequency.
关掉所有无线电通讯工具
Cut all radio communication.
重复一遍, 关掉所有无线电通讯工具
Repeat-- Cut all radio communication.
依顿
Ethan!
Ethan...
莎拉
Sarah.
中止任务, 重复一遍, 中止任务
Abort. Repeat--abort.
中止任务!
Abort!
你们收到了吗?
Do you read me?
莎拉?
Sarah?
天啊!
God!
嘉丽!
Claire!
噢, 我的天哪!
Oh, my God!
我的天哪!
My God!
噢, 不… 莎拉…
Oh, no...Sarah...
第七号卫星通信
Satcom Seven.
中欧, 信号未加密
Central Europe, unsecured.
代码?
Designator?
BE11
Bravo Echo One One.
转接中
Switching.
我是奇佐治
This is Kittridge.
先加密
Go secure.
好了, 说吧
O.K., go ahead.
我是依顿·韩特
This is Ethan Hunt.
他们都死了
They're dead.
谁死了?
What--Who's dead?
我的队员! 我的队员全死了
My team. My team is dead!
天哪
Jesus.
葛里森死了
Golitsyn's gone.
他们知道我们要来
They knew we were coming, man.
他们知道我们要来, 磁盘也被拿走了
They knew we were coming, and the disk is gone.
你没受伤吧?
Are you intact?
磁盘被拿走了, 你听明白了吗?
The disk is gone, do you read me?
名单外流了
The list is in the open!
听着, 我听明白了
Listen, I read you.
我们先把你带到安全的地方, 然后再担心那些, 好吗?
Let's just bring you in safely and then we'll worry about that, O.K.?
有人跟踪你吗?
Were you followed?
应该没有, 应该没有
I don't think so. I--I don't think so.
不要应该, 要确定
Don't think. Be sure.
你没受伤吧?
Are you clean?
是的
Yes.
好, 一个小时之后, 代号绿地点见
O.K. Iocation green, one hour.
我会单独去的
I'll be there myself.
你在布拉格?
You're in Prague?
一个小时之后
One hour.
我…
I, uh--
我不知道怎么表达我有多么的遗憾
I can't tell you how, uh, sorry I am.
我知道占士对你非常特别, 依顿
I know how much Jim, in particular, meant to you, Ethan...
无论是私人关系还是工作关系
personally as well as professionally.
是的
Yeah.
这里是… 护照、维萨信用卡, 和平常一样
Here's a passport, visa. Usual drill.
我们会到加拿大的兰里 听取你们这次行动详细情况
We'll work the exfiltration through Canada debrief you at Langley...
然后扔几个骨头给布拉格警方, 你知道的, 交出几个嫌疑犯就没事了
throw the Prague police a bone or two. You know, toss them a few suspects.
你明白了吗?
You follow me?
是的, 我明白了
Yeah, I follow.
我觉得这个晚上 我们已经失去太多的特工了
I think we've lost enough agents for one night.
你是说我这个晚上 失去了太多的特工
You mean, I've lost enough agents for one night.
你好像在责怪自己, 依顿
You seem hell-bent on blaming yourself, Ethan.
还有谁活下来了?
Who else is left?
是的, 我明白你的意思
Yeah. I see your point.
为什么那里还有其他的小组?
Why was there another team?
什么?
What?
IMF 的特工今晚在大使馆里
Of IMF agents at the embassy tonight.
我不是很明白你的意思
I don't quite follow you.
看看这个店里的人你就明白了
Well, let's see if you can follow me around the room.
七点钟到八点钟方向的 是堤旁的那个俄国醉汉
The drunk Russians on the embankment at 7:00 and 8:00.
九点钟到十一点钟方向的 是那对围着我跳华尔兹的夫妇
The couple waltzing around me at the embassy at 9 and 11.
十二点钟的那个打蝴蝶结的 是在楼梯上面站在汉娜后面的服务生
The waiter standing behind Hannah at the top of the stairs-- bow tie, 12:00.
IMF 的另一个小组
The other IMF team.
你在担心我, 为什么?
You're worried about me. Why?
近两年我们 IMF 的任务经常被破坏, 有人渗透了进来
Well, for a little over two years we've been spotting serious blowback in IMF operations. We have a penetration.
前几天, 我们在互联网上解码了一个消息
The other day, we decoded a message on the lnternet...
由一个被称作马克斯的捷克人发出的
from a Czech we know as "Max."
是一个军火商
The arms dealer.
没错
That's right.
看起来马克斯好像有两个独特的天赋
Max, it seems, has two unique gifts--
隐藏身份和收买特工
a capacity for anonymity and for corrupting susceptible agents.
这次他好像接触到了内部的人
This time, he'd gotten to someone on the inside.
他就是要购买 NOC 名单的人
He'd gotten himself in a position to buy our NOC list.
他从内线得知了"314 行动", 以为就是葛里森今晚要执行的任务
An operation he referred to as job 314-- the job he thought Golitsyn was doing tonight.
但是葛里森偷走的那个名单是个诱饵
But the list Golitsyn stole was a decoy.
那个是假的, 真的名单在兰里受到了严密保护
That's correct. The actual list is secure at Langley.
葛里森只是个幌子, 他是我们的人
Golitsyn was a lightning rod. He's one of ours.
这次的整个行动是为了清除叛徒
This whole operation was a molehunt.
这次的整个行动是为了清除叛徒…
是的
Yeah.
非常狡猾的叛徒…
The mole's deep inside...
而且就像你说过的…
and like you said...
你幸存下来了
you survived.
我想给你看些东西, 依顿
I want to show you something, Ethan.
自从你父亲过世之后
Since your father's death...
你家的农场就在进行破产清算
your family's farm has been in receivership...
而现在, 突然之间 银行帐户里多出了十二万
and now, suddenly, they're flush with over 120 grand in the bank.
你父亲的病应该已经 把银行帐户里的钱用光了
Your father's illness was supposed to have wiped out that bank account.
毕竟他在美国是病了好长时间才死的, 肯定花费了很多的积蓄
Dying slowly in America, after all can be a very expensive proposition.
所以…
So...
为什么现在我们 不安静地离开这里去坐飞机呢?
why don't we quietly get out of here and onto a plane?
我能明白你现在非常混乱
I can understand you're very upset.
奇佐治, 你从没见过我混乱的样子
Kittridge, you've never seen me very upset.
好了, 亨特, 够了够了
All right, Hunt. Enough is enough.
你受贿、诈骗、谋杀
You have bribed, cajoled, and killed...
你利用自己人之间的信任做出了这些事
and you have done it using loyalties on the inside.
你想与恶魔握手, 这对我来说无所谓
You want to shake hands with the devil, that's fine with me.
我只想确认你究竟做没做这些事
I just want to make sure that you do it in hell.
前几天, 我们在互联网上解码了一个消息…
The other day, we decoded a message on the lnternet...
由一个被称作马克斯的捷克人发出的
from a Czech we know as "Max."
他就是要购买 NOC 名单的人
He'd gotten himself in a position to buy our NOC list.
他从内线得知了"314 行动"
An operation he referred to as job 314.
“连接网络”
314 行动…
Job 314...
“未搜索到该字符串”
314 行动, 314 行动…
Job--Job--Job 314. I can't...
行动…
Job...
“滚动新闻组网络系统”
“圣经”
约伯记 3:14? (与"314  行动"同字)
Job 3:14?
约伯记 3:14…
Job 3:14...
混蛋
Oh, you son of a bitch.
“搜索: 圣经”
“找到 126 项指定内容”
“搜索: 约伯记”
“约伯记讨论组” “章: 3;  节:14”
“收件人: 马克斯@约伯记 3:14” “寄件人: 约伯”
“货物已受污染, 及其危险, 千万勿用”
…世上的君主和智者…
建造现已颓倒的殿堂…
依顿…
Ethan...
你在做什么?
what are you doing?
我要你来帮忙, 依顿, 我要你来桥上救我…
I needed you, Ethan. I needed you on the bridge...
但是你没去
but you weren't there.
依顿…
Ethan...
依顿?
Ethan?
不许动
Don't move.
依顿…
Ethan...
依顿, 没事了
Ethan, it's O.K.
冷静一下
Just calm down.
我是嘉丽
It's Claire.
没事了
It's O.K.
你当时在车上
You were in the car.
没有, 我没在车上
No, I wasn't.
我在无线电里听到…
I heard on the radio--
闭嘴! 我看到你了, 你当时在车上
Shut up! I saw you. You were in the car.
没有, 我后来从车里出来了
No. I got out of the car.
我跑向桥那里
I ran to the bridge.
他说有人…
He said someone was--
不用骗我了
Don't give me that.
我当时就在桥上
I was on the bridge.
桥上没有一个人
There was nobody on the bridge.
占士发生了什么事?
What happened to Jim?
醒醒吧, 嘉丽, 占士死了
Wake up, Claire! Jim's dead!
他们死了, 他们都死了!
They're dead! They're all dead!
谁派你来找我的?
Who sent you for me?
占士死了?
Jim's dead?
谁派你来的?
Who sent you here?
占士…
Jim...
脱掉你的外衣
Take off your coat.
你当时在哪?
Where were you, huh?
我…
I--
你当时在哪?
Huh? Where were you?
我走了
I walked away.
他说中止任务, 我就离开了
He said abort. I just...walked away.
那是四个小时之前
That was four hours ago.
谁派你来的?
Who sent you?
-他们派你来找我的吗? -他们指谁?
Did they send you for me? Who's "they"?
他们派你来的吗?
Did they send you?
谁派你来的? 谁派你来的?
Look, who sent you? Who sent you?
没有谁派我来, 没有谁派我来
No one sent me. No one sent me.
我们当时定好四点回到这里的
We were supposed to be back here at 4:00, 4:00.
如果我们失败了, 我们就四点之后回到这里
If we abort, we don't return here until 4:00, 0400, 4 a.m.
四点, 依顿, 四点…
4:00, Ethan. 4:00...
如果我们失败了… 四点
If we abort...4 a.m.
我被逐出来了
I've been disavowed.
他们竟然认为是我杀的占士和其他人
They actually think I killed Jim and everyone else.
不知道为什么有十万美元 被发现存到我父母的银号帐户里
Somehow $100,000 finds its way into my parents' bank account.
奇佐治已经认定 我就是那个他们要查的叛徒
Kittridge assumes I'm the mole they've been tracing...
而且我就是被那个 叫马克斯的军火商雇佣的人
and I've been in the employ of an arms dealer, Max...
在这两年为他偷取我们的 NOC 名单
for the last two years... to get him our NOC list.
你接下来准备怎么办?
What are you going to do?
我打算去了解一下他
I'm going to get it for him.
依顿, 你这么做没有任何意义
Ethan, you're not making any sense.
不管叛徒是谁…
Whoever the mole is...
我觉得应该从行动的名称查起
I think goes by the name of Job.
我虽然找不到他
I can't find him...
但是如果他知道我有 NOC 名单
but if he knows I have the NOC list...
他会来找我的
he'll find me.
我会回去亲自和奇佐治说明白
I'm going to go in and I'm going to talk to Kittridge myself.
我会告诉他, 你和这件事没有任何关系
I'll tell him you had nothing to do with this.
嘉丽, 只要你没死 他就会认为你和我是同伙
Claire, if you're not dead he's going to assume you're with me.
讯息等候中
发给约伯的消息
The message is for Job.
没错
That's right...
而且我会去答覆它
and I'm going to answer it.
“一点在那卡赞卡街和普里考培街的拐角”
“买包登喜路香烟然后 和坐在汽车站长椅上的男人借火”
对不起
Excuse me.
可以麻烦你借个火吗?
Can I trouble you for a match?
可以摘下你的帽子吗?
Would you remove your hat, please?
为什么?
Why?
你想见到马克斯吧?
You wish to meet Max?
这是准许见面的代价
The price of admission.
我想见的是马克斯
I thought I was going to see Max.
你误会了, 没有人能见到马克斯
You misunderstood. No one sees Max.
那我来这里做什么?
Then what the hell am I doing here?
让马克斯见见你, 然后听听你有什么说的
Allowing Max to see you and hear what you've got to say.
我不习惯带着头罩和别人交流
Well, I don't communicate very well through a shroud.
如果马克斯不满意你所说的话, 你就会永远带着那个头罩了
Well, if Max doesn't like what you have to say you'll be wearing that shroud indefinitely.
我想碰碰运气
I'm willing to take the chance.
很好
Very well.
你是谁, 还有你来这里做什么?
Who are you and what are you doing here?
我要十五万美元
I need $150,000.
真的吗?
Ha ha ha. Oh, really?
你… 你以为…
You--You-- And you thought...
你只要简单地开个价, 我就会拱手给你吗?
if you simply showed up I might give it to you?
为什么不会? 你给了约伯十二万
Why not? You gave Job 125.
我已经明白了, 你不是约伯
Hmm...the penny drops. You are not Job.
约伯在联络消息里不喜欢引用圣经
Job is not given to quoting scripture in his communications.
还有那个语气, 很强硬却又有点幽默
Then there was its tone-- aggressive but playful.
约伯一点也不幽默的
Job is not playful.
所以你那些话很矛盾
So you are something of a paradox.
那取决于…
Well, that depends.
什么?
On what?
你喜不喜欢矛盾喽
Whether you like a paradox.
我今天就要拿到十五万美元
I want $150,000 today.
不行, 那绝对不可能
Ah, no. That's quite out of the question.
约伯卖给你的磁盘一文不值
The disk Job sold you-- it's worthless.
那是个诱饵, 用来清除内部叛徒的
It's bait--part of an internal molehunt.
那你怎么知道这些的?
And how might you know that?
你也是另一个内部的人吗?
Are you another company man?
就像约伯?
Like Job?
我在问你
We're asking about you.
我是 NOC, 曾经是, 现在被逐出来了
I'm NOC-- Was-- Now...disavowed.
为什么, 我可以问问吗?
Why, may I ask?
这也是我想问约伯的问题
That is the question I want to ask Job.
我了解约伯的程度不比他了解我的多
I don't know Job any more than Job knows me.
虽然如此, 我相信你也能安排我们认识一下
Even so I'm sure you could arrange an introduction.
我为什么要这么做?
Why should l?
因为我能拿出一份真正的 NOC 名单
Because I can deliver the actual NOC list.
你拿到的那个不但一文不值
The one you have is not only worthless...
而且肯定还装上了跟踪装置, 用来定位你们的精确位置
it's certain to be equipped with a homing device to pinpoint your exact location.
用一下这张盘试试
Boot it up.
无论在哪里, 只要用三十秒到十分钟
In anywhere from 30 seconds to 10 minutes...
以后就会有弗吉尼亚农夫 像野兔一样一直围着你转了
you'll have Virginia farmboys hopping around you like jackrabbits.
把这张磁盘贬成一文不值很容易
It's easy to say the disk is worthless...
你又说我不能查看它的内容, 也就无法知道它是不是真的一文不值
when you say I can't look at the information and see if it's worthless--
这可站不住脚啊, 先生
not a tenable position, sir.
好吧, 那你就用吧
O.K., use it...
但是我建议你先收拾好东西
but... I'd suggest you pack first.
26、27, 到目前为止都还不错
26-27. So far, so good.
对你来说不是好消息, 我的朋友
Not so good for you, my friend.
你还有两分钟
I'd say you've got about two minutes.
32、33
32 and 33.
那不是信号
Doesn't mean it's a signal.
可能是硬盘的发热
Could just be the hard drive heating up.
44、45
44 and 45.
上
Now.
他人已经躲起来了, 巴恩斯
Man's gone black, Barnes.
只有他想露面时才能找到他
He's under until he decides to surface.
我们可以利用大使馆的人, 包括地方当局
We can use somebody at the embassy. Involve the local authorities.
我们可以切断他的交通…
We can cut off his transportation--
我们能怎么做, 巴恩斯?
What can we do, Barnes?
在机场派人守着?
Put a guy at the airport?
你知道亨特同时有着多少个身份吗?
How many identities do you think Hunt has?
从多少个国家的海关, 神不知鬼不觉地溜过去多少次吗?
How many times has he slipped past customs in how many countries?
这些家伙被训练的像幽灵一样
These guys are trained to be ghosts.
是我们把他们训练成这样的, 看在老天的份上
We taught them to do it for Christ's sake.
那么你说该怎么办?
Well, what do you suggest?
我们不能浪费时间追捕他
Let's not waste time chasing after him.
我们要让他主动来找我们
Let's make him come to us.
每个人都有弱点的, 巴恩斯
Everybody has pressure points, Barnes.
你去找出来对他来讲最重要的东西, 然后你就施压
You find something that's personally important to him and you squeeze.
巩特尔再也不会让我借用他的公寓了
Gunther will never let me have one of his apartments again.
刚才怀疑了你我很抱歉, 你很有风度, 亲爱的
Sorry I doubted you, dear boy. You are a good sport.
谢了, 马克斯…
Thanks, Max.
还是该叫你玛克辛?
Or is it Maxine?
我没有必要回答你
Ha ha. I don't have to tell you...
干我这行隐姓埋名会让人很安心
what a comfort anonymity can be in my profession.
就像一个取暖的毛毯
It's like a warm blanket.
我和约伯交易的条件是 磁盘必须能成功的完成引导检测
My deal with Job was subject to a successful boot scan.
很明显它不符合要求, 交易取消了
Obviously it didn't pass muster. Deal's off.
你给约伯开的价是多少?
What was your deal with Job?
六百万美元
Um...$6 million.
我也会给你这么多, 但是我想要完整的名单
I'll give you the same but I want the complete list now...
不仅仅是东欧部分的
not just Eastern Europe.
这种事太危险了, 我不想一次次地干了
I won't do this piecemeal. It's too dangerous.
一千万
10 million.
一千万可兑现的不记名美国国库券, 附上息票
10 million in negotiable U.S. Treasury certificates in bearer form, coupons attached...
而且还有一件事
and one more thing.
你必须保证约伯也在交易现场
Your personal assurance that Job will be at the exchange.
马克斯和你做了笔生意?
Max made a deal with you?
我只要交出 NOC 名单, 马克斯就交出约伯
I deliver the NOC list, Max delivers Job.
我们找到了 75 发用于 你那把贝瑞塔(Beretta)手枪的子弹
We've got 75 rounds for your Beretta...
但是却只找到 20 发 席格索尔(Sig Sauer)手枪的子弹
but only 20 for the Sig Sauer.
一副装有监视器的 Visco 牌眼镜
One pair of Visco glasses with monitor.
好多的护照, 还有…
Plenty of passports, and...
怎么了?
What?
你自己说过的…
You said it yourself...
如果我没死, 他们就会认为我和你是同伙
if I'm not dead, I'm with you.
你真的要这么做?
Are you sure about this?
占士是我的丈夫
Jim was my husband.
我想找出来是哪个混蛋干的
I want to get the son of a bitch who did this.
我们会需要一些帮助
We're going to need some help.
我们没有太多的时间, 所以帮手必须要在本地找
We don't have a lot of time so they're going to have to be local.
需要什么样的帮忙?
What kind of help?
“输入类别” “已被逐出人员”
简单的游戏
Simple game.
四个玩家
Four players.
一个负责打开目标入口
Exfil opens the pocket.
一个负责偷出来钱包
Cyber Ops lifts the wallet.
银行?
Bank?
IMF 主机
IMF mainframe.
确切位置在哪?
Where exactly is it?
在兰里
In Langley.
在兰里? 弗吉尼亚的兰里?
In Langley? The one in Virginia, Langley?
在兰里的 CIA(中央情报局) 总部里面?
Inside CIA headquarters at Langley?
他是认真的吗?
Is he serious?
他一直这么认真
Always.
如果我们要去弗吉尼亚
If we're going to Virginia...
我们为什么不顺便逛逛纳克斯堡金库?
why don't we drop by Fort Knox?
我可以驾驶直升机从门廊直穿过去
I can fly a helicopter right in through the lobby...
然后在金库的里面降落
and set it down inside the vault...
这都比侵入 CIA 要简单很多
and it would be a hell of a lot easier than breaking into the goddamn CIA.
我们要下载什么?
What are we downloading?
资料
Information.
什么资料?
What kind?
有用的资料
Profitable.
交货时付款
Payment on delivery.
我不知道, 我不很确定
I don't know. I just don't know.
这看起来可不像我听说的路德·斯帝盖尔
Well, this doesn't sound like the Luther Stickell I heard of.
他们怎么称呼你的, 是网络骑兵吧?
What did they call you, the Net Ranger?
还是"线上的菲尼亚斯"?
Phineas Phreak?
世上唯一真正侵入了 北约"幽灵网络系统"的人
The only man alive who actually hacked NATO Ghostcom.
从来没有任何证据 能证明我参与过那件…
There was never any physical evidence that I had anything to do with that...
那件…
with that...
那件极为杰出的作品
that exceptional piece of work.
你并不知道你将要错过的是什么
You don't know what you're missing.
这是黑客世界的珠穆朗玛峰
This is the Mount Everest of hacks.
你只是在哄你自己
You're all kidding yourselves.
就算用最顶级的新型解码器、 存取器、3S 测试系统…
Even with top of the line crypto cray access, STU 3s--
克里格能弄到手, 对吧?
Krieger can get it, right?
可能会花一些时间
May take a little time.
"一些时间"是指什么意思?
What the hell do you mean, "a little time"?
嘉丽向我 介绍你的时候可没说过这些
That's not what Claire tells me about you.
我要台笔记本电脑
Thinking-machine laptops.
我是说那种带有 人工智能保险芯片的 686 型
I'm talking about the 686 prototypes with the artificial intelligence risk chip.
二十四个小时之内弄到
24 hours.
还有…
And, uh...
完事的时候我要留下那些设备
I get to keep the equipment when we're done.
路德, 我猜你现在已经没有借口了
Luther, I guess you're all out of excuses.
你瞧…
Look, uh...
我不能用我以前的方法入侵系统
I just can't hack my way inside.
主机上没有装调制解调器
See, there's no modem access to the mainframe.
它是一个独立的系统, 所以我们要真正地在终端上操作
It's in what we call the stand alone which means I'll have to be physically at the terminal.
放松些, 路德
Relax, Luther.
事实比你想像的糟糕多了
It's much worse than you think.
终端放置于密闭的保险库中
The terminal is in a black vault lockdown.
唯一允许进入那个房间的人 必须经过一连串的安全检查
The only person allowed in the room has to pass through a series of security checks.
威廉·丹罗
William Donloe.
第一项检查是 声波纹识别和六位的密码
The first is a voiceprint identification and a six-digit access code.
这项只能让他进入外层房间
This only gets him into the outer room.
接下来, 他必须通过视网膜扫瞄
Next, he has to pass a retinal scan.
最后, 只有使用一个双精度 电子密钥卡才能解除入侵防范系统
And finally, the intrusion countermeasures are only deactivated by a double electronic key card...
我们没有那张卡
which we won't have.
进入保险库之后, 里面有三个运行着的系统
Now, inside the black vault there are three systems operating...
只要操作员离开房间, 第一个声音感应系统就启动了
whenever the technician is out of the room. The first is sound sensitive--
任何稍微大一点的声音都会触发它
anything above a whisper sets it off.
第二个系统检测温度的增长
The second system detects any increase in temperature.
未经授权进入室内的人的体温 将会触发它, 哪怕才仅仅一度
Even the body heat of an unauthorized person in the room will trigger it if the temperature rises just a single degree.
温度是由装在距离地面三十英尺的 高架管道上的空气调节装置控制的
That temperature is controlled by the air-conditioning coming in through an overhead duct 30 feet above the floor.
那个通风口由激光网防护着
That vent is guarded by a laser net.
第三个系统是 装在地面上的压感探测装置
The third system is on the floor and is pressure sensitive.
重量的轻微增长就会触发警报
The slightest increase in weight will trigger the alarm...
而且其中任何一个系统被触发, 都会自动将房间封闭
and any one of these systems if set off, will activate an automatic lockdown.
相信我, 先生们, 我所说的这三个系统, 都代表了现今的最高科技水平
Now...believe me when I tell you, gentlemen all three systems are state-of-the-art.
那么你真的认为我们能办得到?
And you really think we can do this?
我们办得到
We're going to do it.
“兰里”
我们收到在 3、7、12 区域有火警
We picked up alarms in sector 3, 7, and 12.
是的, 我也收到了
Yeah, that's what I've got, too.
空气调节装置在哪一区?
What sector's the air-conditioning?
21 区, 但是 21 区没有火警
21--but there's no alarm in sector 21.
我必须到那里把它关闭了
I got to get in there and shut it down.
任何人都不能进入没有火警的区域
Nobody gets into any sector where an alarm hasn't gone off.
你想让火势蔓延到整栋大楼?
You want to blow the fire through this whole building?
不, 但是任何人都不能进入没有 火警的区域, 而且 21 区并没有火警
No one goes into any sector where the alarm hasn't gone off and it hasn't gone off in 21.
等等
Wait.
那里有火警了, 我们走
It's gone off.
走吧
Let's move.
用我帮你带点东西吗?
Can I get you anything?
不了, 谢谢
No, thank you.
21 区就在这里
21's through here.
“后勤部”
他在招募人手, 为了什么目的?
He's recruiting. For what purpose?
为了生存
Survival.
目光太短浅了, 这个家伙开始行动了, 他一般都主动出击的
Too shortsighted. This guy initiates. He's proactive.
问题是, 他到底想要什么?
The question is, what does he want?
他需要在哪弄到它?
Where does he need to get it?
巴恩斯, 那些该死的噪音是怎么回事?
Barnes, what the hell's that noise?
是火警, 吉恩
Uh, fire alarm, Gene.
我们必须疏散吗?
Do we have to evacuate?
你们本来有三个人的, 另一个家伙哪去了?
Hey, there were three of you. Where's the other guy?
不能杀人
Zero body count.
看看吧
We'll see.
你好啊
Hi there.
一
1.
二
2.
三
3.
吐司
Toast.
蛋糕
Cake.
很好
Good.
好了, 路德, 我要进去了
O.K., Luther, I'm going in.
珠穆朗玛峰啊, 老兄
Everest, man.
你准备好在上面插个旗帜了吗?
You ready to plant the flag?
该死
Damn.
克里格, 从我进去的时候开始, 要绝对地安静
Krieger, from here on in absolute silence.
他正在往你们那里去了
He's rolling to you.
他正在声波纹的那个走廊
He's at the voiceprint corridor.
威廉·丹罗
William Donloe.
外层房间
Outer room.
他正在进入保险库
He's coming in the vault.
快点, 离开
Come on, move.
他在厕所
He's in the bathroom.
输入姓名，威廉丹罗
A-W-9
A-W-9...
6-B-6
6-B-6.
圣母玛利亚啊
Holy mother of God.
NOC 名单!
The NOC list.
下载至名单档
下载程序完成
他进保险库里了
He's at the vault.
四格黄
Four yellows.
一格红
One red.
赶快离开
Get moving.
吐司
Toast.
(法语) 谢谢
Merci.
“按键记录--文件下载  9:58AM”
噢, 天哪
Oh, my God.
是
Yeah.
打给… 你的
It's...for you.
奇佐治
Kittridge.
只有你和我知道这件事, 这件事到此为止了, 你明白吗?
You and I know about this. That's where it stops, you understand?
这件事从来就没有发生过
It never happened.
那他怎么办?
What about him?
我要他在今天就去阿拉斯加守雷达塔, 把他的衣服都寄过去
I want him manning a radar tower in Alaska by the end of the day. Just mail him his clothes.
“伦敦”
你正在联系你的买主?
You contacting your buyer?
依顿
Ethan.
“马克斯: (圣经中箴言) 或与有金子, 将银子装满了房屋的王子一同安息”
依顿
Ethan.
对不起, 亨特先生
Excuse me. Mr. Hunt.
不带上我你别想和任何人见面
You're not going to any meeting without me.
我的联络人非常地害羞的
My contact is extremely shy.
我觉得你没有什么立场能命令我
I don't think you're in any position to give orders...
是吗?
do you?
因为手里有这个
Not while I'm holding this.
克里格…
Krieger...
你是指这个吗?
Oh, you mean this?
那个并不是名单
That's not the list.
怎么了, 你从来没见过这个戏法吗?
What's the matter? You've never seen this trick?
哪去了?
Where'd it go?
不见了
It's gone.
什么?
What?
-你拿去了 -不是
You. No.
不是?
No?
不要了, 拜托
No, come on.
但是不会跑太远
But not too far.
我知道你现在正在想什么, 克里格
I know what you're thinking, Krieger.
你在回想当时主机房里 "我"在上面, "他"在下面
You're thinking back in the computer room, I was up here, he was...he was down there.
是的, 而且他还拿着两张盘
Yes, and he was...he was carrying two disks.
很难把这些事都记清楚
So hard to keep track of these things.
它哪去了?
Where is it?
你真以为我会让你拿到 NOC 名单吗?
Do you actually think l'd let you have the NOC list?
敢对我的钱耍什么花招的话, 我就剪断你的喉咙
Try any sleight of hand with my money and I'll cut your throat.
“由犹太勇士放置于 芝加哥德雷克大饭店”
You're off on one of your cushy...
又是刚刚结束舒适的招募新人的任务?
recruiting assignments again?
这次他们让你住在哪儿了? 纽约大饭店?
Yeah. Where'd they put you up this time, the Plaza?
芝加哥德雷克大饭店
Drake Hotel, Chicago.
我很抱歉
I'm so sorry.
克里格是我找来的
Krieger was my call.
抱歉, 依顿
I'm sorry, Ethan.
大家都是不得已的
We did what we had to do.
我尽量去睡会
I'm going to try and get some sleep.
克里格真的拿到了 NOC 名单?
Krieger did have the NOC list?
现在我想让你拿好它
Now I want you to hold on to it.
为什么你会相信我?
What makes you trust me?
因为如果一开始你就知道 要偷什么的话, 你是绝不会参与的
Because if you knew what you were getting into you never would have done it.
我不会让这个流传出去的
I'm not going to let this get out in the open.
正是如此, 这就是你明天在火车上的任务
Exactly. That's your job tomorrow on the train.
不能让这份 NOC 名单流传出去
Don't let this NOC list get out in the open.
这个东西的有效范围是多大?
What is the range of this thing?
很难说
It's hard to tell.
我到时候必须尽量离近一些
I'm going to have to be close.
依顿, 我得和你谈谈
Ethan, I need to talk to you.
没想到在处于美国腹地的 威斯康星州的一个农场里
The unlikely setting-- a farm in the heartland of America the state of Wisconsin--
联邦特工声称搜捕到了 一个国际贩毒集团的幕后首脑
where federal agents claim to have found the brains behind an international drug ring.
其活动是由玛格丽特·依顿·韩特 以及其小叔子唐纳德·亨特策划的
The operation was masterminded by Margaret Ethan Hunt and her brother-in-law Donald Hunt.
今天早上缉毒官员 在"长刺行动"中逮捕了他们
They were arrested this morning by Drug Enforcement Officers in a major sting operation...
这次行动揭露了他们 非法加工俗称"猫"的麻药甲卡西酮
designed to expose the illegal manufacture of the drug methcathinone, known as Cat.
恐怕在这里找到的…
I'm afraid what we have here...
奇佐治
Kittridge.
我看见你公开拜访了我的家人
I see you've been out visiting the folks.
是亨特, 找出他的精确位置
It's Hunt. What do you need for a pinpoint?
你已经看过了一些电视节目, 对吧?
You've been watching a little TV, have you?
把我的妈妈关进监狱羁押起来 的确是个非常漂亮的手法
Hauling Mom off to jail in shackles was an especially nice touch.
他在英国
He's in England.
接通 M.I.5 (英国情报局)
Get M.I.5.
依顿, 我向你保证
Ethan, I want to assure you...
你自首之后, 我第一个工作就是 撤诉针对你家人的荒谬的指控
that my first order of business after you come in is to have these ridiculous charges against your family dropped...
并且完全销毁他们的所有案卷
and eliminated completely from their files.
如果你… 如果你现在就自首, 我们一样可以减轻对你的指控
If you, uh, if you come in now we can plea down the charges against you as well.
我可以问你一些事情吗, 奇佐治?
Can I ask you something, Kittridge?
当然行, 依顿
Certainly, Ethan.
如果你正在对付的人…
If you're dealing with someone...
他用电梯压死、用刀刺死、开枪射死、 用炸弹炸死了自己小组的五名队员
who's crushed, stabbed, shot, and detonated, five members of his own IMF team...
你觉得把他的妈妈和唐纳德叔叔 送进法院能使他崩溃到什么程度?
how devastated do you think you're going to make him by marching Ma and Uncle Donald down to the county courthouse?
我不知道, 依顿, 你何不告诉我?
I don't know, Ethan. Why don't you tell me?
失去连接
Lost him.
只要再有三秒钟就可以了
We needed three more seconds.
他想让我们知道他在伦敦
He wanted us to know he was in London.
你真是个不容易赶上的人
You're a hard man to catch up with.
第二天我设法拖着自己 回到了一个安全之处
The next day I managed to drag myself back to the safe house.
我肯定是刚巧和你们错过了
I must have just missed you.
总之我查了一下大家的化名
Anyway, I checked our aliases.
而你的化名是你在美国 和我们结识时用的那个
And that's when you picked us up in the States.
但是在我到达之前你又离开了, 而且我能查的只有这些地方而已
But you left before I could get there and I could check just so many places.
-小国的海关记录没有计算机化 -所以我留意到欧洲
Smaller countries don't computerize customs records. So I watched Europe.
你以前在英国待过, 要找起来很容易
Once you turned up in England, it was easy.
你知道我喜欢在利物浦大街租房子住
You knew I liked the rentals at Liverpool Street.
那地方是我告诉你的
Hey, I showed them to you.
我记着呢
I remember.
瞧瞧, 你以为自己在这里正在和谁说笑?
Look, who do you think you're kidding here?
你都无法坐直了, 应该考虑去看医生
A doctor's got to look at that. You can't sit up straight.
我能坐直的
I can sit up straight.
我只是不能坐的非常直而已
I just can't sit up straight very well.
坐下来, 坐下来, 这个并不重要
Sit down. Sit down. It's not important.
依顿
Ethan...
我看到了是谁开枪射我的
I saw who shot me.
我看到了叛徒
I saw the mole.
是奇佐治
It was Kittridge.
奇佐治…
Kittridge.
是奇佐治, 依顿
Kittridge, Ethan.
奇佐治就是叛徒
Kittridge is the mole.
天哪, 当然, 你说的没错
My God, of course. You're right.
他那晚也在大使馆
He was at the embassy that night.
首先, 他在电梯那里除掉了杰克
First, he took out Jack at the elevator.
他在桥上开枪射了你
He shot you on the bridge.
依顿!
Ethan!
他肯定是又回到栅栏那里 除掉了葛里森和莎拉
He must have had backup to take out Golitsyn and Sarah at the fence.
他是怎么对付汉娜的呢?
How did he do Hannah?
不, 不, 他应该是自己动手杀了汉娜的
No. No. He could have done Hannah himself.
为什么, 占士?
Why, Jim?
为什么?
Why?
虽然你这么想, 依顿, 但那是不可避免的
When you think about it, Ethan, it was inevitable.
没有了冷战
No more cold war.
没有了除了自己其他人都不知道的秘密
No more secrets you keep from everyone but yourself.
只有谁都不管的任务
Operations--you answer to no one but yourself.
接着有一天你醒悟了
And then one day you wake up.
美国总统并不是按你的意愿在治国
The President of the United States is running the country without your permission.
狗娘养的, 他竟敢这样
The son of a bitch. How dare he?
然后你认识到一切结束了
Then you realize it's over.
你只是不值得升级的硬件上的一块废料
You're an obsolete piece of hardware not worth upgrading.
你的婚姻很糟糕 而且每年只有六万两千美元
You've got a lousy marriage and 62 grand a year.
奇佐治…
Kittridge...
我们追查那个一无是处的人渣太长时间了
we'll go after the no-good son of a bitch big time.
我们以后不必再这样了
We won't have to.
他将会追查我们
He'll come after us.
为什么他会那么做?
What's going to make him do that?
他在布拉格没拿到的是什么东西?
What he didn't get in Prague.
NOC 名单
The NOC list.
天哪, 依顿
Jesus, Ethan.
你真伟大
Good for you.
明天在开往巴黎的 TGV 上会面 (TGV: 往返巴黎与里昂间的高速火车)
A meeting tomorrow on the TGV, en route to Paris.
严格的安检, 不允许带枪, 很有利
Tight security. No guns. A real plus.
如果我按照预料的 把 NOC 名单交给了马克斯
If I supposedly deliver the NOC list to Max...
马克斯已经同意了把约伯交给我
Max has agreed to deliver Job to me.
我会带着嘉丽和路德·斯帝盖尔 跟我一起上火车
I'll have Claire and Luther Stickell with me on the train.
克里格会驾驶直升飞机在巴黎待命
Krieger is going to have helicopter transport waiting in Paris.
占士?
Jim?
依顿, 刚才我在咖啡屋等你的时候
I was in a cafe waiting for you, Ethan.
她伫立在雨中
And there she was standing in the rain...
活生生而且那样美丽, 以为我已经死去
alive and beautiful thinking I'm dead and gone.
天知道她接下来还得做什么, 是忘掉我, 然后继续向前走…
God knows what she's had to do to forget me, to keep going to get the job done.
不能让她知道我还活着, 依顿
She can't know about me, Ethan.
任何人都不能知道, 直到这件事完结为止
No one can. Not till this is over.
你或许是对的
You're probably right.
风险太大了
There's too much at stake.
占士, 我们离开咖啡屋之后, 你就在那里住下来休息
Once we leave the safe house, Jim you get in there and crash.
我会在巴黎联络你
I'll call you from Paris.
你放心吧
You got it.
“明天中午 TGV 上见面, 坐在 27 号座位, 带上我们共同的朋友约伯”
发生了什么事?
What happened?
我给马克斯发了消息
I sent the message to Max.
我们定在了明天
We're on for tomorrow.
好的
O.K.
到这儿来
Come here.
长官
Sir.
这是什么?
What's this?
收到的, 长官, 是寄给你的
Incoming, sir, for you.
X 射线检查没有问题, 有电子设备, 没有爆炸物
X-ray's clean. Electronics, and no explosives.
“高速列车, 伦敦车站, 中午”
吉恩
Gene?
到伦敦车站要多长时间?
How long to the London terminus?
二十到二十五分钟
20, 25 minutes.
给你十分钟, 行动
You've got 10 minutes. Move!
喂?
Yes?
让马克斯接电话
Give me Max.
是他
It's him.
我们商量的可不是这个样子
This was not what we discussed.
我道歉, 马克斯, 这实在没有办法
My apologies, Max. It couldn't be helped.
在你的座位下面有一件黑色衣服, 剥下来, 你就会找到磁盘的
There's a piece of black cloth under your seat. Tear it away, and you'll find the disk.
情报员名单 “身份完全吻合”
亲爱的…
Dear boy...
我希望这不会妨碍我们的私下见面
I hope this doesn't preclude a meeting in private.
只要你告诉了我钱放在哪里
Not as long as you tell me where the money is.
这丁点见面的可能还是值得我花一千万的
The mere possibility is worth 10 million.
钱放在行李车厢的第三个支架上
Baggage car, rack three.
银色公文包, 开锁码是 314
Silver briefcase, combination 314.
那约伯呢?
What about Job?
不用担心他
Wouldn't worry about him.
你拿到钱之后, 他自会去找你
When you get the money, he'll find you.
“调制解调器连接失败”
怎么了?
What's the matter?
无法传送
It's not transmitting.
试试, 再试试
Try it--try it again!
该死, 我必须在进入隧道之前传送完
Damn it, I've got to get this through before we hit the chunnel.
怎么回事?
What's the problem?
“锁定信号源 传送干扰信号”
连接被拒绝了
Connection denied.
我自己看得见
I can see that.
检查过电池了吗?
Did you check the batteries?
我肯定检查过电池了
I always check the batteries.
那就不要让我看到这些, 从头开始检查
Don't you give me that. Run it through from the top.
真是乱来
This is bullshit.
我们连马克斯长什么样子都不知道
We don't even know what Max looks like.
我们不需要知道
We don't need to know.
如果他拿到了名单, 他会急于先核对它
If he's got that list, he's going to want to check it.
那就意味着要有笔记本电脑
And that means laptops.
对不起, 先生
Excuse me, sir.
你的电话吗?
Your telephone?
我什么听不到
I can't hear anything.
没什么问题吧, 先生?
Is everything all right, sir?
只是有块电池不见了而已
It's just the battery is gone.
可以了
It's working.
“传送中”
他在行李车里
He's in the baggage car.
依顿
Ethan...
奇佐治在火车上
Kittridge is on the train.
我在你后面
I'm right behind you.
钱放在行李车厢
The money's in the baggage car.
我们在那里碰头
I'll meet you there.
巴恩斯?
Barnes?
依顿在我后面
Ethan's right behind me.
听着, 占士
Listen, Jim...
杀了他不太好吧?
is it such a good idea to kill him?
奇佐治在这儿
Kittridge is here.
我们拿了钱, 让依顿背黑锅
We take the money... Ethan takes the blame.
没有其他人看到你还活着
No one else has seen you alive.
没有人会相信他的
No one will believe him.
当然了…
Of course...
你刚才说的那些让我很遗憾, 嘉丽
I'm very sorry to hear you say that, Claire.
依顿
Ethan...
没错
Yes.
你还记得依顿·韩特吧, 亲爱的?
Ethan Hunt, darling. You remember him, don't you?
你知道占士没死?
You knew about Jim?
当然了
Of course.
只是他什么时候确切知道的就是个问题了
Just exactly when he knew is something of a question.
介意告诉我吗, 依顿?
Mind telling me, Ethan?
是我出现在伦敦的之前还是之后?
Before or after I showed up in London?
在去伦敦之前
Before London.
但是在你从芝加哥德雷克大饭店 拿走圣经之后
But after you took the Bible from the Drake Hotel in Chicago.
他们在上面留记号了, 是吧?
They stamped it, didn't they?
那群该死的犹太人
Those damn Gideons.
依顿…
Ethan...
如果你知道了占士的事, 那为什么…
if you knew about Jim, why--
为什么你还要假装这样?
Why the masquerade?
为什么还要冒这个险?
Why take the risk?
嘉丽, 你问到点子上了, 而且你就是答案
Well, Claire...you've asked the question. And you are the answer.
我清楚了占士的事
I knew about Jim.
但是他不知道你是不是也参与了
But he didn't know about you.
老实说, 依顿, 我从来不确定 嘉丽的魅力肯定能迷住你
In all fairness, Ethan... Claire was never convinced her charms would work on you.
但是我试过货色, 绝对有自信
But I was supremely confident having tasted the goods.
朋友妻不可欺, 依顿
Thou shalt not covet thy neighbor's wife. Ethan.
我们赶快拿了钱离开这里吧
Let's just get the money and get out of here.
没错, 我们先拿了钱
Yes, let's get the money.
依顿, 钱呢
Ethan...the money.
把钱交给她
Give her the money.
这是你赚的
You've earned it.
一千万都在这儿
All 10 million.
你知道吗, 嘉丽说错了一件事, 占士
You know, Claire was wrong about one thing, Jim.
是什么呢?
What's that?
早上好, 费尔普斯先生
Good morning, Mr. Phelps.
我并不是唯一看到你活着的人
I'm not the only one who's seen you alive.
你这个混蛋
You son of a bitch.
一切都结束了, 占士
It's over, Jim.
不要
Don't.
不要, 占士
Don't, Jim.
"不要, 占士"?
"Don't, Jim"?
“连接终止, 传送失败”
该死!
Damn!
它在隧道里
No, it's in the tunnel!
不, 不要, 它会撞上我们的
No, no, don't! It'll crash into us!
加速, 加速!
Accelerate! Accelerate!
红灯
Red light!
绿灯
Green light!
你要找的是这个吧
I think this is what you're looking for.
你好, 马克斯
Hello, Max.
我的律师会让你们好看的
My lawyers are going to have a field day with this.
-诱人犯罪, 越权执法… -也许我们可以私下处理
Entrapment, jurisdictional conflict-- Well, maybe we'll just leave the courts out of this one.
我敢肯定, 我能找到一些你们需要的东西
I'm sure we can find something I have that you need.
在一场奇特的事故中
In a freak accident...
一架直升机失控飞进了隧道中
a helicopter lost altitude, veered into a tunnel...
然后和一列从伦敦 高速驶向巴黎的火车相撞
and collided with a high-speed train on its way from London to Paris.
直升机驾驶员死亡, 但是火车上却无一人受伤
The pilot was killed but no one on the train was hurt.
权威人士称事故原因是机械失灵…
Authorities have attributed the accident to instrument failure...
见到你家人了?
Reach your folks?
他们有什么感想?
How do they feel?
关于什么?
About what?
司法部门赔礼道歉, 还有受到 VIP 待遇…
The apology from the Justice Department, VIP treatment--
你知道的, 那有多么的隆重
You know, the whole 9 yards.
我妈妈有点不明白…
Well, my mom was a little confused...
为什么 DEA 会错把她和唐纳德叔叔… (DEA: 美国药品管理局)
how the DEA could mistake her and Uncle Donald...
当成两个佛罗里达的违禁药品走私犯
for a couple of dope smugglers in the Florida Keys.
干杯
Cheers.
敬你一杯, 路德
To you, Luther.
祝贺你重返局里
For being off the disavowed list.
我现在可是风靡一时哦
Hey, I'm the flavor of the month.
你为什么不和我一起回去?
Why don't you come back with me?
我只是…
I just...
我只是不知道为了什么而做那些工作
I just don't know why I'd be doing it.
我差不多该上飞机了
Got to go catch my flight.
重新成为优秀公民的感觉怎么样?
So how does it feel to be a solid citizen again?
伙计, 我不知道
Man, I don't know.
我会怀念声名狼藉时的日子的
I'm going to miss being disreputable.
路德, 如果这样能让你感觉不错
Well, Luther, if it makes you feel any better...
我会一直记着那时的你的
I'll always think of you that way.
打扰一下, 亨特先生
Excuse me. Mr. Hunt?
你要看部电影吗?
Would you like to watch a movie?
不了, 谢谢
no, thank you.
看看这部加勒比海的影片怎么样?
Would you consider the cinema of the Caribbean?
或者是阿鲁巴岛的?
Aruba, perhaps?